The shift is about to hit the fan.
I Am is a documentary film directed by Tom Shadyac.
I AM is an utterly engaging and entertaining non-fiction film that poses two practical and
provocative questions: what’s wrong with our world, and what can we do to make it better?
The filmmaker behind the inquiry is Tom Shadyac, one of Hollywood’s leading comedy practitioners and the creative force behind such blockbusters as “Ace Ventura,” “Liar Liar,” “The Nutty
Professor,” and “Bruce Almighty.”  However, in I AM, Shadyac steps in front of the camera to recount what happened to him after a cycling accident left him incapacitated, possibly for good.
Though he ultimately recovered, he emerged with a new sense of purpose, determined to share his own awakening to his prior life of excess
and greed, and to investigate how he as an individual, and we as a race, could improve the way we live and walk in the world.
Self, played by Marc Ian Barasch.
Self, played by Coleman Barks.
Self, played by Noam Chomsky.
Self, played by John Francis.
Self, played by Lynne McTaggart.
Self, played by Tom Shadyac.
I Am is a 2010 American documentary film written,
directed, and narrated by Tom Shadyac.
The film asks the question: "What is wrong with the world, and what can we do about it?", and explores Shadyac's personal journey after a bicycling accident
in 2007 which led him to the answers "the nature of humanity", "the world's ever-growing addiction to materialism", and "human connections".
Shot with Shadyac and a team of four, the film contrasts sharply with the director's most notable comedic works, such as Ace
Ventura: Pet Detective, Liar Liar, and Bruce Almighty, all of which he collaborated with Canadian comic actor Jim Carrey.
The film explores themes of materialism, laboratory,
scientifically inaccurate, cooperation, human spirit.